A Guide to the University of Virginia College of Arts and Sciences Records of the Ad Hoc Committee on Women's Studies, 1974-1978
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
University of Virginia College of Arts and Sciences Records of the Ad Hoc Committee on Women's Studies 1974-1978
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
RG-6/2/3.841
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
This collection was an archival transfer through Joseph C. Miller, chair of the committee, March 20, 1984.
Scope and Content
The records include correspondence, memoranda, reports, printed material, notes on interviews with department chairs, and course listings.
The Committee's final report, March 27, 1978, includes a subcommittee report on women's studies at other universities, a subcommittee report on interviews with chairs of departments in the College of Arts and Sciences, and a preliminary proposal from the Women's Alliance for a women's studies area program.
The records also include a copy of the report "The status of women faculty at the University of Virginia," March, 1974, which was compiled by the Committee on the Status of Women on the Faculty.
Contents List
- Correspondence and Memoranda, 1977 March- 1978 July, n.d. (Folder 1)
- Notes re Committee Meetings and Women's Studies, 1977 April- 1978 March (Folder 1)
- Guidelines and Preliminary Rreports of Committee Interviews with Department Chairmen, 1977 October- 1978 January (Folder 1)
- Report: "The Status of Women Faculty at the University of Virginia", 1974 October (Folder 1)
- "Report of Women's Studies to Examine Women's Studies Programs at Other Colleges and Universities", 1977-1978 (Folder 1)
- "Women's Studies Area Program: Preliminary Proposal," Presented by the Women's Alliance, 1977 November 29 (Folder 1)
- Drafts: "Report of the Dean's Ad Hoc Committee on Women's Studies", 1978 March (Folder 1)
- "Report of the Dean's Ad Hoc Committee on Women's Studies", 1978 March 27 (Folder 1)
- Printed and Near-print Material re Women's Studies, 1975-1978 (Folder 1)
- Newspaper Clippings re Women's Studies, 1977 December- 1978 April (Folder 1)